Big ideas
	Activist thinking
		see the system
		actively listen
		ask questions
		be the change you want to see
		diversify the people around you
		speak up
	Valued Action
		Resilient
			Flexibility
			Acceptance
			Begin Again
		Brave
			Nonviolent Communication
			Do > Think
			Speak up
		Kind
			Give benefits
			See the Path of Least Resistance
			Reframe
	Better Decisions
		Widen your options
			Vanishing options tests
			Multitrack
			Ask someone who’s already done it
		Reality-test your assumptions
			zoom in, zoom out
			do tiny experiments to test it
			consider the opposite
		Attain some distance
			How would you advise a friend
			Try the 10/10/10 exercise
			Compare to your core values
		Prepare to be wrong
			bookend the future
			set up tripwires
			do a premortem and a preparade
	Start where you are
		Let go
		Accept yourself as you are
		Confront yourself with honesty and a sense of humour
		let pain soften you, wake you up
	Made to Stick
		Simple
			Core and compact
		Unexpected
			Break their guessing machines
			Make it post-dictable
			Curiosity gap
		Concrete
			Helps people understand and remembermber
			More hooks is better
		Credible
			Make it here, make it anywhere
			Make a falsifiable claim
		Emotional
			Appeal to identity
		Stories
			Stories > Arguments
			Inspirational
	Learning
		Avoid illusions of knowing with frequent low-stakes quizzes
		Make mental models
		Practice: mix it up, interleave it. Adds context, meaning
		Three elements of reflection
			retreival
			elaboration (images, own words, connections)
			generation (try first, then view answer)
		Three cognitive multipliers
			growth mindset
			deliberate practice
			memory cues (e.g. mind palace)
		best way to learn is active retrieval. It interrupts the forgetting process.
		Difficulties are good because the learning it stronger. More effort to retrieve makes it stickier.
	Counter spiralling
		Buddhism
			Begin again
			Emotional outshift
			Pay more attention
		Stoicism
			Judgevents
			Reframe
		Psychology
			Focus on the limits
	Buster Benson bias list
		Unfamiliar
		Pride
		Ambiguous
		Inexperience
		Rejection
	Conversation
		In
			Active listening
			Without judgement
			Ask questions
			Is it true, useful, kind?
		Out
			Unpack it
			Share the bad stuff
			One story at a time
			Go first
			Keep showing up
			Show restraint
	The ideas
		Thinking, fast and slow
		Growth Mindset
	Moments
		Elevation
			Raise the stakes
			Turn up the volume
			Break the script
		Pride
			multiple finish lines
			pre-plan actions
			recognise others
		Insight	
			trip over the truth
			Self-insight comes from action, not vice versa
		Connection
			Shared struggle
			Synchronised
			Meaningful
	Switch
		Rider
			follow the bright spots
			destination postcard
			script the critical moves
		Elephant
			find the feeling
			shrink the change
			growth mindset
		Path
			tweak the environment
			make it a habit
			rally the herd
		Fundamental Attribution Error
			the situation, not the person
	Three realms of disagreement
		true
		useful
		meaningful
	Atomic Habits
		Attractive
			temptation bundling
			peer support
		Satisfying
			track progress
		Easy
			prime the environment
			small and quick at first
		Obvious
			implementation intentions
			habit stacking
	Mind Palace
		It’s your judgement that upset, not the thing itself
		These things don’t stop you from being a good person
		Recommitment to valued action
		The trichotomy of control
		“I’ve done this too"
		Contemplate the sage
		Be happy with less, now
		Reframe it
		The three chair exercise
		The future has multiple paths
		The view from above: time, space; Momento Mori
		The obstacle is the way
		The tao of improv
		Do tiny experiments
	Antifragile
		Keep your options open
		stick to simple rules
		respect old, long-lived, habits and rules
		have skin in the game
		take small risks, do small experiments
		build in redundancy, no SPOFs
		avoid bad over seeking good
		barbell strategy: one safe, one speculative
